aj2967@hotmail.com



AJAYBIR **SINGH**

https://www.linkedin.com/in/aj2967/



PROFILE

Self-motivated, resilient, and dedicated BSc (Hons) Computer Science graduate who has simultaneously managed my studies whilst working part time in a fastpaced food chain. I have gained a wealth of knowledge during my studies and internship, having the opportunity to develop knowledge and skills in Computing. Gaining a wealth of industry experience, creating software product to meet the needs of my client.

SKILLS

- MS Office: Word, Excel, PowerPoint, Publisher
- **Programming Languages:** HTML, CSS, SASS, JavaScript, Php, MySQL, C#
- Web Skills: Responsive web design, Bootstrap
- Adobe Software's: Photoshop, Illustrator
- Personal Skills: Ambitious, Fast learner, Problem solver, Good communicator

PROJECTS

Automotive Innovations

A website on presenting the latest news on car innovations

A responsive front-end developed website that serves as a platform to congregate and deliver engaging news and articles.

LakeFront Lodging

A hotel reservation website to allow quests to book rooms

Users can sign in and book selected rooms with the information stored into the database for all guests.

EDUCATION

BSc (Honors) Computer Science | De Montfort University

2017 - 2020

- Achieved upper second classification (2:1) degree
- Learnt to code different languages such as HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Java, Php, MySQL
- Worked with databases using MySQL, and different operating systems such as Linux
- Developed a web application with user login and booking system for final year project.

A level | The City of Leicester College

2015 - 2017

• A Level qualification in Business Studies, Psychology, and ICT

GCSE | The City of Leicester College

2014 - 2015

• 7 GCSE's including Math's and English

EXPERIENCE

Web Developer | Future Care Internship

FEBRUARY 2021 - APRIL 2021

- Draft website wireframe designs and documentation based on client's requirements.
- Developed and implemented required pages for the project about creating an interface for baby monitoring devices
- Implementing a login system for pages with restricted content
- Worked in a team to successfully produce the initial interface and members area for a service that will allow its users to monitor various elements such as temperature of a baby using the baby monitoring device.

Team Member | KFC

AUGUST 2018 - JUNE 2021

- Communicated effectively with customers and colleagues during busy periods.
- Ensured hygiene assurance and quality standards were met when preparing food.
- Effectively assisted customers to resolve any complaints in a calm and professional manner.

Brand Ambassador | 7 Miles Marketing

AUGUST 2017 – NOVEMBER 2017

- Liaised with a variety of customers to sell a variety of products to customers
- Provided excellent customer service by learning to interact with the community